CONTACT INFORMATION Rm 614, Kelvin Building University of Glasgow Glasgow, G12 8QQ United Kingdom Work: +44 (0)14133 08855 Web: www.pauljwright.co.uk Email: paul.wright@glasgow.ac.uk Publication List: SAO/NASA ADS

RESEARCH INTERESTS My interests range from stellar to solar physics; my main interests lie in the heating of the solar atmosphere, including active regions and loops. I have expertise in analysis of data from SDO/AIA, Hinode/EIS, Hinode/XRT, and NuSTAR Solar observations.

EDUCATION

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK

2014 – present (expected 2018)

Ph.D. Solar Physics

Thesis Topic: *The Energetics of Small Flares and Brightenings* Advisers: Dr Iain G. Hannah, Dr Alexander MacKinnon

University of Southampton, Southampton, UK

2010 - 2014

MPhys Astrophysics with a year abroad

First class honours (1:1) Adviser: Professor Malcolm Coe

Harvard University/Harvard-Smithsonian CfA, Cambridge, MA

2013 - 2014

MPhys Astrophysics with a year abroad

Thesis Topic: *Superflare Rates of Solar-Like Stars* Advisers: Dr Steven H. Saar, Dr Jeremy J. Drake

CURRENT ACADEMIC APPOINTMENT

Affiliate Staff Member, University of Glasgow SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy

2017 – present

 Investigating the non-flaring coronal time-series data for signs of the coronal heating mechanism.

PREVIOUS
ACADEMIC
APPOINTMENTS

Post-Graduate Research Assistant, University of Glasgow

2014 - 2017

SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy

Project: The Energetics of Small Flares and Brightenings

- Analysed observations of the Sun with *NuSTAR*, a telescope not designed for heliophysics. These observations are the most sensitive of their kind and have resulted in numerous, wide-ranging highly-collaborative peer-reviewed publications.
- Analysed non-flaring coronal time-series in order to extract signatures of the coronal heating mechanism. Techniques included Fourier analysis, Wavelet analysis, and Local Intermittency Measure.
- Studied the temperature distribution of the solar atmosphere through the recovery of an ill-posed inverse problem using techniques such as Tikhonov Regularization, Markov-Chain Monte Carlo, and Sparsity.

Collaborators: Iain Hannah, Alexander MacKinnon

Visiting Researcher, NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC)

2016

Heliophysics Science Division

• Worked on the possibility of implementing DEM maps in the Helioviewer project, and their usefulness as an input for various established analysis techniques.

Collaborators: Nicholeen Viall, Jack Ireland

Research Scholar, Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics (CfA) 2013 – 2014 Solar and Stellar X-Ray Group

• Designed and implemented a sophisticated stellar flare detection routine for long-cadence (30 mins) *Kepler* data. This work has had coverage by Science, and The Smithsonian Magazine.

Collaborators: Steven Saar, Søren Meibom, Jeremy Drake, Vinay Kashyap

| REFEREED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS | [1] Marsh, A. J., Smith, D. M., Glesener, L. et al 2017. First NuSTAR Limits of Sun Hard X-Ray Transient Events, ApJ (in revision) | on Quiet | |
|---|--|----------|--|
| | [2] Wang, J., Simões, P. J. A., Jeffrey, N. L. S. et al 2017. Observations of Reconnection Flows in a Flare on The Solar Disk, ApJL, 847, L1 | | |
| | [3] Wright, P. J., Hannah, I. G., Grefenstette, B. W., et al 2017. Microflare Hea Solar Active Region Observed with NuSTAR, Hinode/XRT, and SDO/AIA, A 132 | | |
| | [4] Kuhar, M., Krucker, S., Hannah, I. G., et al 2017. Evidence of Significant Input in the Late Phase of a Solar Flare from NuSTAR X-ray Observation 835, 6 | | |
| FIRST AUTHOR PUBLICATIONS IN PREPERATION CONFERENCES, | [5] Wright, P. J., Hannah, I. G., Viall, N. M., et al | | |
| | [6] Wright, P. J., Saar, S. H., Meibom, S., et al | | |
| | Invited Oral Presentations | | |
| WORKSHOPS, & | ISSI Team Meeting: Coronal Nanoflares, Bern, CH | 2016 | |
| SCHOOLS | Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, Cambridge, MA, USA | 2014 | |
| | | 2014 | |
| | Oral/ePoster Presentations | | |
| | Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS), Portland, OR, USA | 2017 | |
| | Coronal Loops Workshop VIII, Palermo, Sicily, IT | 2017 | |
| | Living with a Star (SDO/LWS) Workshop, Burlington, VT, USA | 2016 | |
| | Hinode 10, Nagoya, JP | 2016 | |
| | National Astronomy Meeting 2016, Nottingham, UK | 2016 | |
| | Hinode 9, Belfast, UK | 2015 | |
| | Glasgow-Cambridge Flare Workshop, Glasgow, UK | 2015 | |
| | Poster Presentations | | |
| | European Solar Physics Meeting (ESPM), Budapest, HU | 2017 | |
| | Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS), Portland, OR, USA | 2017 | |
| | Living with a Star (SDO/LWS) Workshop, Burlington, VT, USA | 2016 | |
| | Coronal Loops Workshop VII, Cambridge, UK | 2015 | |
| | NAM 2015, Llandudno, UK | 2015 | |
| | 223rd AAS Meeting, National Harbor, MD, USA | 2013 | |
| | | 2014 | |
| | Schools Attended | | |
| | CESRA Radio Summer School 2015, Glasgow, UK | 2015 | |
| | STFC Advanced Summer School in Solar Physics, Dundee, UK | 2014 | |
| | Conferences/Workshops Attended | | |
| | NuSTAR Heliophysics Workshop (remote participation), Berkeley, CA, USA | 2017 | |
| | SUPA Cormack Astronomy Meeting, Edinburgh, UK | 2015 | |
| | RAS Discussion Meeting: Results from IRIS, London, UK | 2015 | |
| | SUPA Cormack Astronomy Meeting, Edinburgh, UK | 2014 | |
| | 1st Space Glasgow Research Conference, Glasgow, UK | 2014 | |
| | | | |
| AWARDS AND | SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy, University of Glasgow | | |
| GRANTS TOTAL: £7000 | Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS) Student Poster Award | 2017 | |
| | Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS) Studentship Award | 2017 | |
| | Coronal Loops Workshop VIII Travel Award | 2017 | |
| | National Astronomical Observatory of Japan Travel Award | 2016 | |
| | Hinode 9 Travel Award | 2015 | |
| | European Space Agency/Cambridge Philosophical Society Travel Award | 2015 | |
| | ran arrange - market production | | |

| AWARDS AND | School of Physics and Astronomy, University of Southampton | | |
|----------------------|--|--|--|
| GRANTS (CONT.) | Research Scholarship 2013 | | |
| CRAINTS (CONT.) | Summer Studentship Grant 2013 | | |
| T | | | |
| TEACHING | University of Glasgow | | |
| | Astronomy 1 Tutorial Demonstrator 2016 - 2017 Supervised students, and marked first year astronomy problem sets. | | |
| | | | |
| | Physics Pre-University Summer School 2015 Engaged students in various physics experiments and marked assignments. | | |
| | Astronomy 3/4 (Honours) Laboratory Demonstrator 2015 - 2016 | | |
| | Demonstrated, supervised, and marked a number of final-year research projects cov- | | |
| | ering topics such as asteroid light curves, and solar limb darkening. | | |
| Memberships | NuSTAR Heliophysics Working Group, Member 2015 – present | | |
| WEWELLSTIN S | International Space Science Institute (ISSI), Young Scientist Member 2015 – present | | |
| | Member of Paola Testa's ISSI Team: New Diagnostics of Particle Acceleration in Solar | | |
| | Coronal Nanoflares from Chromospheric Observations and Modeling | | |
| | Royal Astronomical Society , RAS Fellow 2014 – present | | |
| COMMUNITY | Nature Communications, Reviewer 2017 – present | | |
| Involvement | CESRA Radio Summer School, Volunteer Organiser 2015 | | |
| SCIENTIFIC | Glasgow Science Centre, Demonstrator 2016 | | |
| OUTREACH | British Science Week, Demonstrator 2016 | | |
| OUTKEMEN | Institute of Physics: Women and Girls in Science, Demonstrator 2016 | | |
| | Scottish Television (STV), Guest Presenter 2015 | | |
| | World Wide Telescope, Ambassador 2013 – 2014 | | |
| | BBC Stargazing Live, Demonstrator 2013 | | |
| | So'ton Astrodome, Demonstrator 2012 | | |
| | BBC Bang Goes The Theory Roadshow , Demonstrator 2012 | | |
| | UK Solar Physics (UKSP) Nuggets, concise, easy-to-read science articles | | |
| | 84. The first NuSTAR microflare 2017 | | |
| | Hinode/XRT Picture of the Week (XPOW) | | |
| | The First Microflare Observations with Hinode/XRT & NuSTAR 2017 | | |
| PERSONAL PROJECTS | ColourBlind , A repository for colour-blind-friendly colour tables. Citations: 1 | | |
| PROFESSIONAL | Coursera, Inc. (MOOC Platform) | | |
| DEVELOPMENT | Using Coursera.org, a massive open online course (MOOC) platform, to take specializa- | | |
| | tions (sets of multiple courses) offered by accredited universities to further develop skills | | |
| | and understanding in a wide range of computer science applications. | | |
| | Data Science , Johns Hopkins University 2017 – present | | |
| | Nine-course (plus capstone) introduction to data science. | | |
| | Mastering Software Development in R , Johns Hopkins University 2017 – present Four-course (plus capstone) specialization providing riguourous training in the R | | |
| | language. | | |
| | Statistics with R, Duke University 2017 – present | | |
| | Four-course (plus capstone) specialization providing further training in the R lan- | | |
| | guage with emphasis on statistics. | | |

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT (CONT.)

Big Data, UC San Diego

2017 – present

Five-course (plus capstone) introduction to big data using Hadoop with MapReduce, Spark, Pig and Hive.

Machine Learning, University of Washington

2017 - present

Three-course (plus capstone) introduction to Machine Learning.

Graphic Design, CalArts

2017 - present

Four-course (plus capstone) introduction the fundamental skills required to make sophisticated graphic design.

edx, Inc. (MOOC Platform)

Introduction to Computer Science, Harvard University

2017 – present

An introduction to the intellectual enterprises of computer science and the art of programming.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Computing: Python, R, IDL, LATEX, Git, Linux/Unix, Mac OSX, Microsoft Windows, Bash, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Keynote, Wordpress

General: Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Interdisciplinary Collaboration, Public Speak-

ing, Statistics, Teaching, Writing (Technical Lay)

MORE INFORMATION

More information and auxiliary documents can be found at http://www.pauljwright.co.uk,

on ResearchGate, and GitHub.